foreign
[Music]
in the United States age-related hearing
loss affects about a quarter of those in
their 60s more than half of those in
their 70s and 80 percent of those in
their 80s more than 95 percent of
seminarians have been found to have
severe hearing loss because of impaired
communication this may lead to social
isolation loneliness and depression may
even threaten one's life due to an
Associated increase in motor vehicle
accidents what can we do to prevent
age-related hearing loss it's said to be
a natural part of the aging process but
that's what we used to think about
pathological conditions like high blood
pressure
the vast majority of people eventually
develop hypertension just like the vast
majority of people eventually lose their
hearing so it must just be an inevitable
consequence of growing old right
but then it was discovered that there
were rural populations living in Africa
and Asia that Aiden lived healthier that
didn't experience in inexorable rise in
blood pressure as they aged so it
appeared hypertension was more a
lifestyle Choice than an aging effect
and the same may be true for hearing
loss
the mabon tribe living in the Sudanese
desert was found to retain their hearing
into old age other studies on isolated
native population found that exposure to
Modern civilization appeared to undercut
their hearing advantages what is it
about our modern world that appears to
be leading to a loss of hearing as we
grow older age-related hearing loss is a
result of the premature death of the
sensory hair cells in our inner ear
which turns vibrations to electric
signals to the brain once they're lost
they don't grow back so prevention is
critical
the question is what's killing them a
study more than 2 000 twins found that
the heritability of age-related hearing
impairment was only 25 so most of risk
is due to non-genetic influences risk
factors include repeated exposure to
loud noises smoking and ototoxic or
hearing damaging medications noise
exposure early in life proves to render
the inner ear more vulnerable to aging
animal studies suggests exposure to low
level but constant noise over 60
decibels may also be harmful
this has not been demonstrated in humans
but if you use a white noise generator
to sleep it can't hurt to check that
it's under 50. medications known to be
ototoxic include immunoglycoside
antibiotics like strepromycin amicacin
neomycin canomycin which are among the
highest risk medications for hair cell
toxicity but NSAIDs anti-inflammatory
drugs like aspirin ibuprofen and
naproxen and Loop Diuretics for example
a furosemide sold as Lasix have also
been linked to Progressive hearing loss
however the key to the preservation of
old age hearing of the bond tribe may be
their diet
the reason the bond researchers
concluded that their diet likely
accounted for their lack of age-related
hearing loss is because they also appear
to lack something else coronary artery
disease what kills more of us in the
industrialized world than anything else
doesn't appear to touch them at all
their blood pressures are also perfect
their whole lives at about 110 over 70
into their 70s while we on average
become hypertensive exceeding 130 over
80 starting in our 40s and no wonder
their diet is almost free of animal
protein and centered around whole grains
so they suggested in addition to the
absence of loud noise that
atherosclerosis clogging the small blood
vessels feeding their inner ears maybe
the underlying cause of age-related
hearing loss in most of the rest of the
world but you don't know until you put
it to the test which I'll cover next
after dealing with a supplement shown to
slow age-related hearing loss
foreign